<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Commons on Apache Iceberg</title><link>https://iceberg.apache.org/common/</link><description>Recent content in Commons on Apache Iceberg</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://iceberg.apache.org/common/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://iceberg.apache.org/community/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://iceberg.apache.org/community/</guid><description>Welcome! Apache Iceberg tracks issues in GitHub and prefers to receive contributions as pull requests.
Community discussions happen primarily on the dev mailing list, on apache-iceberg Slack workspace, and on specific GitHub issues.
Contributing The Iceberg Project is hosted on Github at https://github.com/apache/iceberg.
The Iceberg community prefers to receive contributions as Github pull requests.
View open pull requests Learn about pull requests Issues Issues are tracked in GitHub:</description></item><item><title/><link>https://iceberg.apache.org/blogs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://iceberg.apache.org/blogs/</guid><description>Iceberg Blogs Here is a list of company blogs that talk about Iceberg. The blogs are ordered from most recent to oldest.
Using Debezium to Create a Data Lake with Apache Iceberg Date: October 20th, 2021, Company: Memiiso Community Author: Ismail Simsek
How to Analyze CDC Data in Iceberg Data Lake Using Flink Date: June 15, 2021, Company: Alibaba Cloud Community
Author: Li Jinsong, Hu Zheng, Yang Weihai, Peidan Li</description></item><item><title/><link>https://iceberg.apache.org/talks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://iceberg.apache.org/talks/</guid><description>Iceberg Talks Here is a list of talks and other videos related to Iceberg.
Expert Roundtable: The Future of Metadata After Hive Metastore Date: November 15, 2021, Authors: Lior Ebel, Seshu Adunuthula, Ryan Blue &amp;amp; Oz Katz
Spark and Iceberg at Apple&amp;rsquo;s Scale - Leveraging differential files for efficient upserts and deletes Date: October 21, 2020, Author: Anton
Apache Iceberg - A Table Format for Huge Analytic Datasets Date: October 21, 2020, Author: Ryan Blue</description></item><item><title/><link>https://iceberg.apache.org/releases/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://iceberg.apache.org/releases/</guid><description>Downloads The latest version of Iceberg is 0.12.1.
0.12.1 source tar.gz &amp;ndash; signature &amp;ndash; sha512 0.12.1 Spark 3.0 runtime Jar 0.12.1 Spark 2.4 runtime Jar 0.12.1 Flink runtime Jar 0.12.1 Hive runtime Jar To use Iceberg in Spark, download the runtime JAR and add it to the jars folder of your Spark install. Use iceberg-spark3-runtime for Spark 3, and iceberg-spark-runtime for Spark 2.4.
To use Iceberg in Hive, download the iceberg-hive-runtime JAR and add it to Hive using ADD JAR.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://iceberg.apache.org/spec/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://iceberg.apache.org/spec/</guid><description>Iceberg Table Spec This is a specification for the Iceberg table format that is designed to manage a large, slow-changing collection of files in a distributed file system or key-value store as a table.
Format Versioning Versions 1 and 2 of the Iceberg spec are complete and adopted by the community.
The format version number is incremented when new features are added that will break forward-compatibility&amp;mdash;that is, when older readers would not read newer table features correctly.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://iceberg.apache.org/terms/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://iceberg.apache.org/terms/</guid><description>Terms Snapshot A snapshot is the state of a table at some time.
Each snapshot lists all of the data files that make up the table&amp;rsquo;s contents at the time of the snapshot. Data files are stored across multiple manifest files, and the manifests for a snapshot are listed in a single manifest list file.
Manifest list A manifest list is a metadata file that lists the manifests that make up a table snapshot.</description></item></channel></rss>