<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Commons on Apache Iceberg</title><link>https://iceberg.apache.org/common/</link><description>Recent content in Commons on Apache Iceberg</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://iceberg.apache.org/common/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://iceberg.apache.org/releases/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://iceberg.apache.org/releases/</guid><description>Downloads The latest version of Iceberg is 0.13.1.
0.13.1 source tar.gz &amp;ndash; signature &amp;ndash; sha512 0.13.1 Spark 3.2 runtime Jar 0.13.1 Spark 3.1 runtime Jar 0.13.1 Spark 3.0 runtime Jar 0.13.1 Spark 2.4 runtime Jar 0.13.1 Flink 1.14 runtime Jar 0.13.1 Flink 1.13 runtime Jar 0.13.1 Flink 1.12 runtime Jar 0.13.1 Hive runtime Jar To use Iceberg in Spark or Flink, download the runtime JAR for your engine version and add it to the jars folder of your installation.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://iceberg.apache.org/blogs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://iceberg.apache.org/blogs/</guid><description>Iceberg Blogs Here is a list of company blogs that talk about Iceberg. The blogs are ordered from most recent to oldest.
Introducing Apache Iceberg in Cloudera Data Platform Date: February 23rd, 2022, Company: Cloudera
Authors: Bill Zhang, Peter Vary, Marton Bod, Wing Yew Poon
Apache Iceberg Becomes Industry Open Standard with Ecosystem Adoption Date: February 3rd, 2022, Company: Dremio
Author: Mark Lyons
Docker, Spark, and Iceberg: The Fastest Way to Try Iceberg!</description></item><item><title/><link>https://iceberg.apache.org/contribute/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://iceberg.apache.org/contribute/</guid><description>Contributing In this page, you will find some guidelines on contributing to Apache Iceberg. Please keep in mind that none of these are hard rules and they&amp;rsquo;re meant as a collection of helpful suggestions to make contributing as seamless of an experience as possible.
If you are thinking of contributing but first would like to discuss the change you wish to make, we welcome you to head over to the Community page on the official Iceberg documentation site to find a number of ways to connect with the community, including slack and our mailing lists.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://iceberg.apache.org/how-to-verify-a-release/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://iceberg.apache.org/how-to-verify-a-release/</guid><description>How to Verify a Release Each Apache Iceberg release is validated by the community by holding a vote. A community release manager will prepare a release candidate and call a vote on the Iceberg dev list. To validate the release candidate, community members will test it out in their downstream projects and environments. It&amp;rsquo;s recommended to report the Java, Scala, Spark, Flink and Hive versions you have tested against when you vote.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://iceberg.apache.org/community/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://iceberg.apache.org/community/</guid><description>Welcome! Apache Iceberg tracks issues in GitHub and prefers to receive contributions as pull requests.
Community discussions happen primarily on the dev mailing list, on apache-iceberg Slack workspace, and on specific GitHub issues.
Contribute See Contributing for more details on how to contribute to Iceberg.
Issues Issues are tracked in GitHub:
View open issues Open a new issue Slack We use the Apache Iceberg workspace on Slack. To be invited, follow this invite link.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://iceberg.apache.org/spec/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://iceberg.apache.org/spec/</guid><description>Iceberg Table Spec This is a specification for the Iceberg table format that is designed to manage a large, slow-changing collection of files in a distributed file system or key-value store as a table.
Format Versioning Versions 1 and 2 of the Iceberg spec are complete and adopted by the community.
The format version number is incremented when new features are added that will break forward-compatibility&amp;mdash;that is, when older readers would not read newer table features correctly.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://iceberg.apache.org/talks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://iceberg.apache.org/talks/</guid><description>Iceberg Talks Here is a list of talks and other videos related to Iceberg.
Data architecture in 2022 Date: May 5, 2022, Authors: Ryan Blue
Why You Shouldn’t Care About Iceberg | Tabular Date: March 24, 2022, Authors: Ryan Blue
Expert Roundtable: The Future of Metadata After Hive Metastore Date: November 15, 2021, Authors: Lior Ebel, Seshu Adunuthula, Ryan Blue &amp;amp; Oz Katz
Presto and Apache Iceberg: Building out Modern Open Data Lakes Date: November 10, 2021, Authors: Daniel Weeks, Chunxu Tang</description></item><item><title/><link>https://iceberg.apache.org/terms/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://iceberg.apache.org/terms/</guid><description>Terms Snapshot A snapshot is the state of a table at some time.
Each snapshot lists all of the data files that make up the table&amp;rsquo;s contents at the time of the snapshot. Data files are stored across multiple manifest files, and the manifests for a snapshot are listed in a single manifest list file.
Manifest list A manifest list is a metadata file that lists the manifests that make up a table snapshot.</description></item><item><title>Benchmarks</title><link>https://iceberg.apache.org/benchmarks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://iceberg.apache.org/benchmarks/</guid><description>Available Benchmarks and how to run them Benchmarks are located under &amp;lt;project-name&amp;gt;/jmh. It is generally favorable to only run the tests of interest rather than running all available benchmarks. Also note that JMH benchmarks run within the same JVM as the system-under-test, so results might vary between runs.
Running Benchmarks on GitHub It is possible to run one or more Benchmarks via the JMH Benchmarks GH action on your own fork of the Iceberg repo.</description></item><item><title>How To Release</title><link>https://iceberg.apache.org/how-to-release/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://iceberg.apache.org/how-to-release/</guid><description>Setup To create a release candidate, you will need:
Apache LDAP credentals for Nexus and SVN A GPG key for signing, published in KEYS If you have not published your GPG key yet, you must publish it before sending the vote email by doing:
svn co https://dist.apache.org/repos/dist/dev/iceberg icebergsvn cd icebergsvn echo &amp;#34;&amp;#34; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; KEYS # append a newline gpg --list-sigs &amp;lt;YOUR KEY ID HERE&amp;gt; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; KEYS # append signatures gpg --armor --export &amp;lt;YOUR KEY ID HERE&amp;gt; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; KEYS # append public key block svn commit -m &amp;#34;add key for &amp;lt;YOUR NAME HERE&amp;gt;&amp;#34; Nexus access Nexus credentials are configured in your personal ~/.</description></item><item><title>Multi-Engine Support</title><link>https://iceberg.apache.org/multi-engine-support/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://iceberg.apache.org/multi-engine-support/</guid><description>Multi-Engine Support Apache Iceberg is an open standard for huge analytic tables that can be used by any processing engine. The community continuously improves Iceberg core library components to enable integrations with different compute engines that power analytics, business intelligence, machine learning, etc. Connectors for Spark, Flink and Hive are maintained in the main Iceberg repository.
Multi-Version Support Processing engine connectors maintained in the iceberg repository are built for multiple versions.</description></item><item><title>Roadmap</title><link>https://iceberg.apache.org/roadmap/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://iceberg.apache.org/roadmap/</guid><description>Roadmap Overview This roadmap outlines projects that the Iceberg community is working on, their priority, and a rough size estimate. This is based on the latest community priority discussion. Each high-level item links to a Github project board that tracks the current status. Related design docs will be linked on the planning boards.
Priority 1 API: Iceberg 1.0.0 [medium] Spark: Merge-on-read plans [large] Maintenance: Delete file compaction [medium] Flink: Upgrade to 1.</description></item><item><title>Security</title><link>https://iceberg.apache.org/security/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://iceberg.apache.org/security/</guid><description>Reporting Security Issues The Apache Iceberg Project uses the standard process outlined by the Apache Security Team for reporting vulnerabilities. Note that vulnerabilities should not be publicly disclosed until the project has responded.
To report a possible security vulnerability, please email security@iceberg.apache.org.
Verifying Signed Releases Please refer to the instructions on the Release Verification page.</description></item><item><title>Trademarks</title><link>https://iceberg.apache.org/trademarks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://iceberg.apache.org/trademarks/</guid><description>Trademarks Apache Iceberg, Iceberg, Apache, the Apache feather logo, and the Apache Iceberg project logo are either registered trademarks or trademarks of The Apache Software Foundation in the United States and other countries.</description></item></channel></rss>