<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Apache Iceberg</title><link>https://iceberg.apache.org/docs/0.13.0/docs/integrations/</link><description>Recent content on Apache Iceberg</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://iceberg.apache.org/docs/0.13.0/docs/integrations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>AWS</title><link>https://iceberg.apache.org/docs/0.13.0/aws/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://iceberg.apache.org/docs/0.13.0/aws/</guid><description>Iceberg AWS Integrations # Iceberg provides integration with different AWS services through the iceberg-aws module. This section describes how to use Iceberg with AWS.
Enabling AWS Integration # The iceberg-aws module is bundled with Spark and Flink engine runtimes for all versions from 0.11.0 onwards. However, the AWS clients are not bundled so that you can use the same client version as your application. You will need to provide the AWS v2 SDK because that is what Iceberg depends on.</description></item><item><title>JDBC</title><link>https://iceberg.apache.org/docs/0.13.0/jdbc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://iceberg.apache.org/docs/0.13.0/jdbc/</guid><description>Iceberg JDBC Integration # JDBC Catalog # Iceberg supports using a table in a relational database to manage Iceberg tables through JDBC. The database that JDBC connects to must support atomic transaction to allow the JDBC catalog implementation to properly support atomic Iceberg table commits and read serializable isolation.
Configurations # Because each database and database service provider might require different configurations, the JDBC catalog allows arbitrary configurations through:</description></item><item><title>Nessie</title><link>https://iceberg.apache.org/docs/0.13.0/nessie/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://iceberg.apache.org/docs/0.13.0/nessie/</guid><description>Iceberg Nessie Integration # Iceberg provides integration with Nessie through the iceberg-nessie module. This section describes how to use Iceberg with Nessie. Nessie provides several key features on top of Iceberg:
multi-table transactions git-like operations (eg branches, tags, commits) hive-like metastore capabilities See Project Nessie for more information on Nessie. Nessie requires a server to run, see Getting Started to start a Nessie server.
Enabling Nessie Catalog # The iceberg-nessie module is bundled with Spark and Flink runtimes for all versions from 0.</description></item></channel></rss>